{
  "age": 54,
  "background": "Attorney/Partner Carney, Kelehan, Bresler, Bennett & Scherr, LLP.  http://www.carneykelehan.com/our-attorneys/darren-burns Practice centers on litigation, particularly cases involving education, commercial construction, employment, contract, business, real property, and cable/satellite piracy issues. His clients include developers, contractors, property managers, retail businesses, restaurants and property owners. He represents his clients in courts throughout Maryland as well as in federal court, administrative hearings, arbitration and mediation. In addition to litigation, Mr. Burns advises clients on contracts and business formation, and he handles regulatory matters before various Anne Arundel County and City of Annapolis agencies including liquor licenses and other trade requirements. An experienced education lawyer, Mr. Burns served for six years as the in-house counsel for the Anne Arundel County Public Schools. He has represented boards of education, local governments and public officials in numerous contract, tort and civil rights cases.    Professionally, Mr. Burns is an officer for the Construction Law Section of the Maryland State Bar Association and former trustee of the Anne Arundel County Bar Association. His two decades of experience in court began with his judicial clerkship for the Hon. Robert H. Heller Jr. in the Circuit Court for Anne Arundel County.",
  "directory": "content/state-house/district-30a",
  "district": "30a",
  "dob": "3/8/1964",
  "education": "College of William & Mary, J.D. (1990) Hampden-Sydney College, B.A. (1986) Severn School (1982)",
  "filename": "b-darren-burns.md",
  "full-name": "B. Darren Burns",
  "general-only": false,
  "headshot": "http://surveygizmoresponseuploads.s3.amazonaws.com/fileuploads/296249/4297291/104-174c2a083d29860dab0eb8d5eb5ddc18_BURNS_darren_photo.pdf",
  "jurisdiction": "Anne Arundel County",
  "last-name": "Burns",
  "party": "Republican",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "In concept, I support the  focus on education policy, goals and structural improvements that the Kirwin Commission sought to address, and  I concur that the funding formula -- like  the setting of priorities -- required a fresh, comprehensive revisit.  At the same time, Maryland's leaders cannot accept that the  answer to  the question, \"How do we take public education to greater success?\" is simply more spending and more taxes.   Equally important is that any initiatives with such state-wide implications must be truly bipartisan and geographically diverse.   Debate  needs to be fully inclusive of all Marylanders' points of view, not merely  those of the dominant political party  or the largest counties.",
      "shortname": "Kirwan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
      "answer": "It's unclear to me whether transportation spending is appropriately balanced between roads and  other forms of transit.   Achieving the balance that is right for Maryland requires an  understanding  of the geographic diversity of our state, because the right choices for the Eastern Shore shore are not the same as for the I-95 corridor or for western Maryland.  And the long-term solutions  for the urban/developed suburban areas around Baltimore and Washington are different from anywhere else, yet must be integrated with the overall plan.  At the same time, we need a realistic assessment of the condition of our existing infrastructure and the need for serious reinvestment in it.  Moreover, how we spend must be predicated on the broader plan, not merely on piecemeal, project-by-project  horse-trading . Governor Hogan appreciates this, and I support his measured approach.",
      "shortname": "Transportation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
      "answer": "No; Maryland has barely begun to implement its medical marijuana initiatives, let alone had time to assess the relative success.  However, some element of decriminalization, and with that less incarceration, appears to have merit.",
      "shortname": "Marijuana"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
      "answer": "The Chesapeake Bay's restoration is not an either/or question, nor is it a state vs. federal question.  Like all bodies of water among our major natural resources  (e.g., the Great Lakes, the Mississippi, the Colorado, the Everglades, the coastal waters, etc.), states  -- and groups of directly impacted states --must take the lead and insist on true partnership  at the federal level.  Maryland should re-start the process by including all stakeholders  (watermen, recreational users, environmental watchdogs, farmers, businesses) in its policy initiatives, in order to balance competing interests and reach compromise wherever possible on what we are trying to achieve.   Then, once we force ourselves to set a mission and strategic goals, we can attack how to reach them.",
      "shortname": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
      "question": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
      "answer": "It's a work in progress, but  somehow we must combine the incredible  excellence of our health  care institutions  and care providers with the  ability of most  income earners to contribute to the cost of care, while funding a reasonable, sufficiently funded safety net for those who truly are without ability to pay for care.  I do not have the answers to this question, but as an elected representative I would call on our best and brightest minds to come together, regardless of party affiliation, to propose solutions.  Adopting/co-opting  recent federal \"universal\" policies is not the answer.",
      "shortname": "Health Care"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
      "answer": "This is a complex issue, with both entrenched causes and  current  driving factors.   Besides the clear need for state and city officials to work cooperatively across party lines to address the problem holistically (education, child-centered  resourcing, illegal gun trade and use, and  consistent, fair law enforcement),  perhaps the State's  most important role for right now is to support the City in its efforts to  reform the Police Department while not demonizing the rank & file.  In addition, State (and City ) officials must hold prosecutors and the courts accountable for convicting and sentencing violent offenders.  The  revolving door of violent recidivism must end.",
      "shortname": "Crime"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
      "answer": "It is improving under Governor Hogan, but there is more work to do.   Government must stop seeing businesses and business owners as merely a taxable resource and instead celebrate them as the engine of prosperity and job creation.   Income comes from productivity, so public policy must favor those who want to promote and  practice being productive, and, in turn,  be financially rewarded for choosing that path rather than a path of subsistence or long-term public dependence.",
      "shortname": "Business Climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
      "answer": "Yes.",
      "shortname": "Redistricting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "The LEOBR reflects a long history of balancing due process for the discipline of police officers with the broader interests of all citizens.  At the same time, like any  law or policy that has been in place for a long time, it is not immune to changing community standards and expectations.  I would support a bi-partisan, diversely constituted panel to review what works, what needs to be updated, and what may no longer serve original policy goals.",
      "shortname": "LEOBR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
      "answer": "We need to continue the efforts of leaders who have been willing to identify the crisis and  implement programs, like Governor Hogan and Anne Arundel County Executive Steve Schuh, and work harder at  funding them.  In addition, we need to incentivize -- or at least remove impediments -- to hospitals,  treatment facilities and other private providers to expand mental and behavioral  response and treatment, including  for addiction.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
      "answer": "There is no magic fix for income inequality in a free society based on  capitalism and  market economy.  To start, we must understand that one key is education and career training, which can provide  families and especially  young people a  path to become income earners in way that they feel they have a stake in the economy and their own future.  In other words, citizens must believe  from their early years that hard work and playing by society's rules will actually  get them where they want to go.   At the same time, government must stop seeing businesses and business owners as merely a taxable resource. and instead celebrate them as the engine of prosperity and job creation.   Income comes from productivity, so public policy must favor those who want to promote and  practice being productive, and, in turn,  be financially rewarded for choosing that path rather than a path of subsistence or long-term public dependence.",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
      "answer": "Yes.",
      "shortname": "Transparency"
    }
  ],
  "race": "state-house",
  "residence": "Annapolis",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "B. Darren Burns"
}
